

Contact Details

Gabriel Díaz Iturry

M gabriel.diaz.iturry

in/gabriel-diaz-iturry

○ /gabo-di

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue

English: Advanced Portuguese: Fluent

Díaz Gabriel Iturry

Physicist - Data Scientist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Nonlinear Dynamics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data and the use of statistical tools to compare data to models. I currently work in web developing and AI integration, using several APIs from Google to OpenAI.

Experience

Jan 2023 - Present

Independent Researcher:

- Research in areas of Time Series analysis using Artificial Intelligence and Data Driven Modeling.
- Web developer, in charge of integrating the AI code with the Web page.

May 2021 - Apr 2023

Data Scientist, Physicist:

- Reproduce state-of-the-art reasearch.
- Deliver the models in a clear and robust interfarce for user consumption.
- Optimization using Operations Research and Heuristics methods for several projects.

Feb 2017 - Feb 2021

Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Research projects include:

- Anomalous Diffusion on Classical Systems.
- Bifurcation Analysis.
- Quantum to Classical transition.

Education

2017 - 2021

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil.

2015 - 2017

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade Estadual de São Paulo (UNESP) São Paulo, Brazil.

2009 - 2014

Bachelor in Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Simón (UMSS). Cochabamba, Bolivia.

Skills

Technical

Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Simulations, Feature Engineering, Data Analysis.

Software Development

Python, R, Julia, Fortran, Golang, Mathematica, MatLab.

Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, seaborn, matplotlib, openCV, nltk, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn, XGBoost, CatBoost.